Το Plex ζήτησε 120€ για να συνεχίσετε να βλέπετε από τις συσκευές σας.
Το πλήρωσα εγώ το ποσό.
Αν χρησιμοποιείτε συχνά και μπορείτε,
οποιαδήποτε συμβολή θα εκτιμηθεί.
This area has always been
difficult to navigate,
so all kinds of things wash up here.
It used to be that the entire village
helped clean up the shore.
But now you don't have enough people,
so it lies neglected.
These waters used to be beautifully clear.
I know.
How about this as payment?
It's a book written by
Flamme the Legendary Mage.
Ms. Frieren.
Is this the only grimoire
you have in your village?
Yes.
Very well. We'll clean up the area for you.
That grimoire is a fake, isn't it?
I see you've been studying like
I told you to. Good girl, Fern.
Books attributed to Flamme are never real.
This is just another poor imitation.
Why did you accept the job?
To help someone in need.
I find that hard to believe.
You're right. I'm doing this for me.
Sounds like we've got another
long stay ahead of us.
Thanks for being such a
regular customer, Fern.
I threw in an extra one for you.
Thank you.
It's been three months already.
Have you gotten used to the village?
Yes.
The shore gets cold this
time of year. Be careful.
It's winter already.
She's still asleep.
This place is a mess.
I just tidied up yesterday, too.
Ms. Frieren, it's morning. Please wake up.
Let's go clean up the shore.
So cold...
I've been thinking.
About what?
Are you actually a very sloppy person?
Every morning I wake you up, feed you
breakfast, and help you get dressed.
I'm practically your mother.
I can do all that myself.
But then you'd sleep until noon.
Yeah.
Well, I've already given up hope, anyway.
Sorry.
How did you manage traveling
with the hero's party?
There wasn't anyone there
to look after you.
I overslept all the time.
And you never got in trouble for it?
I did, just once.
Just once? They must have been very tolerant.
They were a whole different breed.
Also, Heiter sometimes clicked his tongue.
Sorry.
Hey.
I understand how you feel, but...
Sounds like they were rather upset with you.
How is the cleanup coming along?
We have about a third of it left.
Do you think you'll be done in time
for the New Year's Festival?
Just barely.
In that case, I hope you'll be able to watch
the sunrise this time, Ms. Frieren.
Is the beach cleanup related to
the New Year's Festival somehow?
In this village, it's customary to watch the
sunrise on the day of the New Year's Festival.
They say it's beautiful how the light
reflects off the clear waters.
You haven't seen it?
Do you think I'd be able
to wake up that early?
I suppose not.
Let's hurry. We don't have much time.
No problems with the water quality.
We managed to finish by the day before.
It hardly looks like the same beach.
Thank you, Ms. Frieren.
You'll be joining us for the
New Year's Festival, won't you?
Yes.
We'd love to have you.
Have you lost your mind, Ms. Frieren?
You'll have to wake up before the sun rises.
That's impossible for you.
I'll be fine. I just need
to stay up all night.
You're that desperate to see the sunrise?
Honestly, I'm not interested,
which is why I want to see it for myself.
I don't understand.
No, I suppose you wouldn't.
Why didn't you come to the
New Year's Festival, Frieren?
The shock was so great,
it left Heiter bedridden. Poor guy.
He's just out of commission
because he drank too much.
What's the problem?
The rest of you got to go.
We wanted you to enjoy it, too.
It's just a sunrise.
I doubt I'd enjoy it much.
No, you would.
Why?
Because you're that kind of person.
She's asleep.
She's asleep!
Ms. Frieren, wake up.
You'll be late for the New Year's Festival.
Mother...
Who are you calling "Mother"?
Why am I doing this?
Thank you, Fern.
It's certainly pretty, but it wasn't
worth waking up early for.
Himmel didn't understand me after all.
Fern, I'm going home so I can go back to...
Ms. Frieren, it's beautiful.
Is it?
It's just a sunrise.
But you seem to be enjoying
yourself a little.
That's because you're smiling.
I wouldn't have been able to see
this sunrise if I'd been on my own.
Of course not. After all, you can't
get out of bed by yourself.
Are these for your family?
It was a long time ago.
My village was attacked by demons.
What are you doing?
Praying.
People return to nothingness when they die.
No, they go to Heaven.
Until several thousand years ago,
the commonly held belief
was that there was no afterlife.
Dwarves value tradition.
I'm skeptical about the idea
of a heaven myself,
but since current magics can't
observe the souls of the dead,
its existence can't be proven or disproven.
I don't think it matters either way.
You're right. I don't care
if it exists or not.
Should a man of the cloth be saying that,
you corrupt priest?
But even if it doesn't exist,
I believe it should.
Why?
Because it's more convenient that way.
All those people doing their best
to live deserve something better
than nothingness awaiting them.
I prefer to think they get to
live the good life in Heaven.
That certainly is more convenient.
Shall we pray?
Yeah.
Eisen, I'm here to hang out.
You act like it hasn't been thirty years.
What's a mere thirty years?
You're right.
I never thought you'd take on an apprentice.
Eisen, is there anything you need help with?
Frieren, I heard you asked
Heiter the same thing.
I'm not on my deathbed yet.
How do you know about that?
Because we wrote to each other.
You're more conscientious than you look.
You're just too indifferent.
So, do you need help with anything?
Voll Basin...
This place brings back memories.
You've been here before?
A long time ago.
"A long time," she said.
How long must that be?
Perhaps she came here in prehistoric times.
Not even I've lived that long.
So, what are we looking for?
The notes of Flamme the Legendary Mage.
Fine. You know most of Flamme's
supposed writings are fake, though?
I have a lead.
Heiter deduced the location from records
on Flamme left in the holy city.
Her genuine notes are located
somewhere in Voll Basin.
Frieren, you must know that.
That corrupt priest.
He'd gotten that far in his research?
Fine. We'll begin by searching
for a large tree.
A large tree?
That's ridiculous. There are tons of trees.
Well, I suppose you have
all the time in the world.
That's right.
But Fern wouldn't like that,
so I'll try to finish quickly.
Let's search as efficiently as possible.
You've changed.
You never cared about
other people's time before.
Fern is scary when she's mad.
I see. Then I should watch myself.
Ms. Frieren.
There's a large tree to the west
growing over some ruins.
This way.
Got it.
Hey. Why did you decide to
look for Flamme's notes?
Because I felt sorry for you.
What?
I felt sorry for you and Himmel.
On that day thirty years ago,
you said you wished you'd gotten
to know Himmel better.
You should tell Himmel himself that.
They say the notes of Flamme the Legendary
Mage describe her conversing with the dead.
That's just a fairy tale.
Besides, I don't want to see him now.
All magic started as fairy tales.
And don't you want to know more about Himmel?
That's why I talked it over with Heiter.
We were sure you had regrets,
so we wanted to help you.
Ms. Frieren, both the tree and ruins
are protected by a powerful barrier.
Even after a thousand years, I'm still
dancing in the palm of my master's hand.
How's that little sapling going to keep watch?
Don't sell it short.
Once it grows, it'll still be protecting
this place a thousand years from now.
You'll be dead by then.
But you won't be.
Someday, you'll make a terrible mistake
and wish you'd gotten to know people better.
Do you wish I knew you better?
Are you being needy?
Yeah, no.
When that happens, return to this place.
Then I, Flamme the Legendary Mage,
will help you.
Those are Flamme's notes?
Are they real?
They're real.
How do you know that?
Frieren was Flamme's best student.
Flamme the Legendary Mage is an ancient hero
who's written about in magical history.
Are you sure you haven't been
around since prehistoric times?
Does it say anything about
speaking to the dead?
It's already opened to that very page.
Did she know a thousand years ago
that I'd come here?
What an unpleasant woman.
"On the northernmost end of the continent..."
I arrived at the place the people
of this world call heaven:
Aureole, the land where souls rest.
Many souls gather there,
and I spoke with friends
who once fought alongside me.
This discovery of the century...
"... will propel research on souls forward."
Do you suppose it's true?
Who knows? She was an irresponsible person.
Heaven exists.
It's more convenient if it does.
You're right. Perhaps I should
believe in it for once.
Where exactly is this place?
Give me a moment.
The northern continent... Ende.
Ende?
Yes.
It's where the Demon King's
castle is located now.
But why there?
Frieren.
You must find Aureole and speak with Himmel.
You said you'd help me, didn't you?
You've learned some cunning tricks, Eisen.
Thanks to Heiter.
Fine. I didn't have a particular
destination anyway.
But it's so cold around
the Demon King's castle.
I don't want to go.
She's already feeling discouraged.
She fell asleep.
What a carefree girl.
It's cold. I don't want to go.
She's moaning in her sleep.
Is it really that cold around
the Demon King's castle?
Ende, where the castle is, is located at the
very northernmost end of the continent.
We went through a lot in that place.
A lot?
This is awkward.
Maybe I'll wake Ms. Frieren.
Ms. Frieren. Ms. Frieren.
She won't wake up.
Say, Fern. Is she a good master?
That's a good question.
I don't really know.
All she does is drag me around
while she searches for magic.
But she does seem interested in getting
to know Mr. Himmel and his companions.
Perhaps she's not very interested in me.
Ms. Frieren only took me on as an apprentice
because she promised Mr. Heiter she would.
I see.
But she's such a strange person.
After we began traveling together,
she started giving me birthday presents.
Normally she seems so disinterested in me.
I wonder what she's thinking.
She's so strange.
Frieren, you're not going
to stay in the royal capital?
I'm going to keep traveling.
Alone?
It'll be nice and easy.
You're not going to take on an apprentice?
Traveling is better when you
have someone to talk to.
It's a waste of time.
Even if I taught them, they'd die in no time.
Frieren, that's not how relationships work.
Yes, it is.
My adventure with you wasn't even
one one-hundredth of my life.
You must understand that, Eisen.
I...
Okay, okay. That's enough depressing talk.
Today is a day for celebrating. Let's drink.
You just want a reason to drink, don't you?
You saw right through me.
You're always drinking.
You corrupt priest.
Fern...
She's a good master.
You're right.
Eisen, you're really not coming with us?
That's right.
I told you before, I'd only get in your way.
I see.
You remember how to get to Ende, don't you?
Yes. First we travel through the Wille region,
and then we cross Riegel Canyon and pass
through the northern lands checkpoint.
Sorry to ask this of you.
It'll be a long journey.
It took us ten years.
I see.
We'll be following the same path Mr. Himmel's
party took to the Demon King's castle.
You're right.
It'll be a mere ten-year adventure.
Do you think I can become a powerful warrior?
They appear after death.
You really do only collect odd spells.
Travelers, may I have a moment of your time?
Why haven't you defeated the dragon?
You're searching for it, aren't you?
That's ridiculous.
This is a phantom of the dead.